how many of you have ever been through a
tough situation in your life and you
know the phrase that we use for it it
was like we were going through hell I
want to encourage you today if you're
going through a tough situation right
now if you have been through it's a
tough situation in the past or if you
are facing a tough situation in the
future this message is for you today
pray with me Heavenly Father we need a
word from you Lord at one time or
another in all of our lives we either
have or will face situations that try us
to the uttermost situations designed to
break us situations designed to
discourage and so lord please speak to
us today this is our prayer in Jesus
name we ask it amen
I invite you to turn with me in your
Bibles to the book of second chronicles
chapter 36 second chronicles chapter 36
we'll begin reading from verse 15 the
Bible says in the Lord God of their
fathers sent to them by his messengers
rising up betimes and sending because he
had compassion on his people and on his
dwelling place but they mocked the
messengers of God and despised his words
and misused his prophets until the wrath
of the Lord arose against his people
till there was no remedy
therefore he brought upon them the king
of the Cowley's who slew their young men
with the sword in the house of their
sanctuary and had no compassion upon
their young man upon young man or made
an old man or him that stooped for age
he gave them all into his hands let me
ask you a course
would you say that the children of
Israel as a result of their disobedience
went through a pretty hellish experience
here yeah the Bible tells us that that
this King King Nebuchadnezzar king of
Babylon comes upon Israel and takes them
captive verse 18 and all the vessels of
the house of God great and small and the
treasures of the house of the Lord and
the treasures of the King and his
Prince's all these he brought to Babylon
and they burnt the house of God and
break down the wall of Jerusalem and
burnt all the palaces thereof with fire
and destroyed all the goodly vessels
thereof and then that had escaped from
the sword carried he away to Babylon
where they were servants to him and his
sons until the reign of the kingdom of
Persia the children of Israel are
brought to a place called Babylon and if
you know anything about Babylon the one
thing that you should know about Babylon
was that Babylon was a heavily fortified
Kingdom a heavily fortified city there
were two leaved gates that guarded the
city and so the children of Israel in
their hellish experience are brought
into the kingdom of Babylon but praise
God
that God did not leave them in that
hellish experience if you're with me
just say Amen and and and and we know
that God did not leave them in that
hellish situation because in verse 22 of
the same chapter it says now in the
first year of Cyrus king of Persia the
word of the Lord spoken by the mouth of
Jeremiah might be accomplished the Lord
stirred up the spirit of Cyrus king of
Persia that he made a proclamation
throughout all his kingdom and put it
also in writing saying thus saith Cyrus
king of Persia all the kingdoms of the
earth has the Lord God of heaven given
me
he has charged me to build him a house
in Jerusalem which is in Judah who is
there among you excuse me of all his
people the Lord his God be with him and
let him once go up you know who Cyrus is
he was the king of the medo-persian
Empire and and what we are reading here
is that Cyrus is the man that God used
to deliver the children of Israel out of
their hellish experience come again with
me to the book of Isaiah chapter 45
because Isaiah 45 gives us a little bit
more insight Isaiah 45 and verse 1
Isaiah 45 verse 1 thus saith the Lord to
his anointed to Cyrus whose right hand I
have Holden to subdue nations before him
and I will loose the loins of Kings to
open excuse me before him the to leave
gates and the gates shall not be what
shut so listen carefully Cyrus the man
that God would use to deliver the
children of Israel out of their hellish
experience Cyrus is the man that entered
into Babylon by opening up the leaved
gates the same leaved gates that had
held the children of Israel captive in a
hellish experience
please note carefully that Cyrus entered
into that city he entered into that that
place where the children of Israel were
experiencing hell on earth if you will
and Cyrus opened the gates so that the
children of Israel could escape that
hellish experience amen
notice again with me Isaiah chapter 61
speaking of cyrus notice how the Bible
describes him Isaiah 61 verse 1 when
you're there to CNN the Bible says the
Spirit of the Lord God is upon me
because the Lord has anointed me to
preach good tidings unto the meek and
has sent me to bind up the brokenhearted
to proclaim Liberty to the captives and
the opening of the prison to them that
are bound to proclaim the acceptable
year of the Lord
and the day of vengeance of our God to
comfort all that mourn to appoint unto
them that mourn in Zion and to give them
beauty for Ashes the oil of joy for
mourning the garment of praise for the
spirit of heaviness that they might be
called the trees of righteousness the
planting of the Lord that he might be
glorified pause for a second I know what
many of you are thinking right now
pastor this is not talking about Cyrus
but let me tell you it is talking about
Cyrus because God called Cyrus his
anointed and so this scripture the
Spirit of the Lord has anointed me Cyrus
was sent into Babylon into the children
of Israel's hellish experience in order
to set them free from that hellish
experience Isaiah 61 and verse 3 lets us
know how much God cared about Israel you
see through their own sins they had been
led into a hellish experience but by the
grace of God they were able to escape or
come out of that hellish experience amen
in other words while Satan led them into
a hellish experience God led them
through that hellish experience yeah
I don't know if you caught what I just
said while Satan sought to lead them
into a hellish experience God led them
not only into God not only allow them to
go into but he ultimately led them out
of so if you are going into and then
coming out of something what are you
doing you are going through it you
should praise God that you are going
through hell you didn't catch that you
should praise God let me pause come back
with me Genesis chapters 3 Genesis
chapter 3 and I need you to see this
here Genesis chapter 3 verse 15 so
Genesis chapter 3 verse 15 you guys know
what's happening there Adam and Eve have
just sinned and and as a result of by
the way who led them into sin Satan led
them into sin the serpent convinced them
to sin and when they sinned when they
disobeyed God the Bible says that the
wages of sin is what is death so they
brought about death as a result of their
sin and notice with me Genesis 3 verse
verse 15 it says then I would put enmity
between thee and the woman between thy
seed and her seed it shall bruise thy
head and thou shalt bruise his heel and
onto the woman he said I will greatly
multiply thy sorrow and thy conception
in sorrow shalt thou bring forth
children and thy desire shall be to thy
husband and he shall rule over thee and
on to Adam he said because you have
hearken unto the voice of your wife and
have eaten of the tree of which I
commanded thee saying thou shalt not eat
of it cursed is the ground for thy sake
and sorrow shalt thou eat of it all the
days of our life thorns and thistles
shall it bring forth to thee and thou
shalt eat the herb of the field and now
notice verse 19 in the sweat of thy face
shalt thou eat bread till thou watts
return unto though
ground for out of it that was taken for
dust thou art and unto dust shalt thou
wat return let me ask you a question
where is Adam where does Adam go as a
result of his sin where is he going he's
going to the to the ground he's going to
the grave his sin has brought about a
hellish experience for Earth can you say
amen to that I mean not that you want to
say amen to that but his were the same
that is a truth his sin brought about
the unleashed a hellish experience for
mankind and as a result of his sin Adam
and Eve will go to the grave now can
anyone tell me what symbol is used in
the Bible to describe the grave or what
word is used in the Bible to describe
the grave
it's Sheol you know that word is or
Hades that is hell
it's the grave so check the saw gods
when Adam and Eve sinned their sin leads
them to the grave to Hades or to hell
that sounds like a pretty bleak picture
to me what do you think but remember the
promise of genesis 3:15 because God said
I am going to send someone that is going
to defeat the one that led you to sin
now let me ask you what is the good news
about that why was it good news that a
seed would come to this earth who was
that seed Jesus and what would Jesus do
on our behalf he would conquer death
meaning he would open up death to
provide a way for us
he would open up hell did you catch what
I just said he would open up hell to
provide a way for us not to just go into
hell and it end there but for us to go
God sent his son to provide a way for
you and I to go through I shut every
time I see but I just need you to get
the point to go through the grave to go
through not just the grave beloved but
listen carefully to go through those
hellish experiences that are designed to
destroy us you see when Adam and Eve
sinned this world became like hell a
dark sinful world and you need to
understand this because just as cyrus
had to go into babylon in order to
provide a way for those in babylon to
get out of babylon so jesus christ came
down to this earth listen carefully to
go through hell on our they have so
whenever you start thinking man i'm
going to help rejoice because christ
went through it before you and he went
through it so that you and i could go
through it the devils design is to lead
us into hell and to have us perish in
hell
god says no no no no no I'm going to you
Satan you may bring hell but I'm gonna
lead them through it rejoice that you
are going through hell not that you are
in Hell rejoice that God has opened up a
way for you to escape because listen
when Jesus came
need you to see just how much hell Jesus
went through for you and I when he came
to this earth he is not even three years
old and Rome says destroy every child
that could possibly be him you think
that was the hellish experience when he
begins his ministry he has to go into
the wilderness for 40 days and 40 nights
without food do you think that was a
hellish experience he begins his
ministry checklist I'll come with me to
Luke chapter 4 and verse 18 Luke chapter
4 verse 18 very interestingly Jesus when
he begins his ministry uses these words
he is quoting the words that pointed to
Cyrus and here are the words he says he
sit goes to the temple he sits in the
temple and then he picks up the Bible he
reads the Spirit of the Lord is upon me
because he has anointed me to preach the
gospel to the poor he has sent me to
heal the brokenhearted to preach
deliverance to the captives where
captives in hell captives that are that
are discouraged captives that that are
bound by sin captors that had nothing to
look forward to but death he says I have
come to do what Cyrus did literally by
opening the gates I have come to do that
spiritually I have come to open up the
gates of Hell so that you can find a way
through it listen
come with me to Matthew 26 you have to
see this Matthew 26 beginning with verse
20 Matthew chapter 26 and verse 20
Matthew 26 verse 20 here's what the
Bible says it says now when the evening
was come he sat down with the twelve and
as they did eat he said verily verily I
say unto you that one of you shall
betray me and they were exceeding
sorrowful and began every one of them to
say unto Him Lord is it I and he's
answered and said he that dip ahthe his
hand with me in the dish the same is he
that shall betray me
verse 26 as they were eating jesus took
bread and blessed it and break it and
and he gives to his disciples and he
eats and then the very next verses begin
to say that his heart began to be very
sorrowful even unto death what was Jesus
beginning to go through in a very real
sense as he knew he was about to enter
the Garden of Gethsemane he was going
through hell on our behalf when he says
father if it be possible let this cup
pass from me he was beginning to feel
the feeling of the wicked when they will
be separated from God
from the father Jesus in the Garden of
Gethsemane is praying and he's sweating
drops of blood and then we find Jesus on
the cross and he's crying out my God my
God why has not forsaken me they're
mocking him they're spitting on him
they're doing everything in their power
to break him they are putting Jesus
through hell Jesus dies and now he
literally goes into hell the grave death
on our behalf he is in the grave on our
behalf that's why beloved that is why
three days later when Christ comes out
of the check this outcome you got to see
this
how many of you know the twenty-third
song there's one part of that song you
know that Psalm is talking about Christ
right there's one part of that Psalm
that I want you to focus on yay though I
walk what though I walk into I I don't I
don't know if you catch the significance
of this yeah guys yea though I walk not
into yea though I walk through in other
words the death of Christ was to pave a
way through death so that you and I
could have life so that you and I could
walk through death just as he did in
fact come with me acts 2 verse 27 let's
see if we can get that up on the screen
acts 2 verse 27 notice what the Bible
says here speaking of Jesus it says
because that will not leave my soul
where where was Jesus everyone in Hell
and yet the Bible says that his soul
would not be left in hell so when Christ
came up out of the grave what the Bible
is telling us is that Christ literally
went through hell for us don't be afraid
if you're going through hell guys don't
be afraid if you're facing trying times
and trouble of situations because God
has provided a way for you to go through
hell praise God that you can go through
praise God that you can go through hell
because you remember even Jonah as he
was in the belly of the whale even what
Jonah said that he had gone down to err
he had gone down to hell
three days and three nights this is the
exact spirit experience of Jesus Christ
three days and three nights in the belly
of the earth
Hosea 13 verse 14 we want to get that up
on a screen Hosea chapter 13 verse 14
you see Satan led mankind into hell but
through the sea Jesus Christ God would
lead mankind through hell notice Hosea
13 verse 14 I will ransom them from the
power of the grave you know what that
word is Sheol it means hell I will
ransom them from hell from the grave I
will redeem them from death Oh death our
be thy plagues or grave I will be thy
destruction repentance shall be hid from
my eyes now this is why you should
rejoice when reading 2nd Peter chapter 2
come with me 2nd Peter chapter 2 verse 4
2nd Peter chapter 2 verse 4 in fact
that's another verse I'm thinking of
we're gonna come to that leave that up
on the screen the Bible says for if God
spared not the Angels that sinned but
cast them down to where we read he cast
them down to him to hell and delivered
them into chains of Darkness to be
reserved them to judgment let me ask you
a question according to that verse is
Satan in Hell right now according to
this verse the angels and Satan have
been cast down to where to hell now we
know that in this particular contest
we're not talking about the grave
because Satan is not in the grave we're
not talking about he's dead because
Satan is not dead Satan is alive and
well and yet he is where he is separated
from God beloved here and now hell is us
is a
place is a hell is Satan's design to
separate you from God so so when Satan
brings hell upon you when Satan brings
hell in your family when Satan brings
hell at your job
when Satan brings hell between you and
your neighbors between you and your
brother and sister when Satan brings
hell to the church his whole design is
to separate you from God from the
presence and the power of God so Satan
is always seeking to find the best
hellish situation to put you in huh well
how can I put you into hell how can I
make your life hell right now how can I
make things so miserable for you that
you will throw in the towel and give up
on me that's what he does that's what
he's after that's what he's trying to
accomplish he's trying to get you into a
hellish situation but beloved listen to
me there is good news because Christ
said something about his church Matthew
16 verse 18 you remember these words
Christ said I say unto thee thou art
Peter and upon this rock I will build my
church and the Watts gates of Hell shall
not prevail against it did you catch
that beloved that promise is for every
one of you here in the church this
morning Jesus says if you stick with me
the gates of Hell will not prevail
against you what does that mean that
means that the gates of Hell will not be
able to lock you in I'm not going to
leave you in dabble on to be locked in
by these leaved gates no the gates of
Hell will not prevail against you I will
provide a way of escape out of your
hellish situation but
need you to be patient I need you to
endure I need you never to give up on me
I need you to know that I am with you
even through the trial that word Church
in this verse it is a Greek word
ecclesia you know what it means you know
the word it's the first time in the New
Testament the word church is used and
the word means I love this who the word
means called out ones did you catch that
called out called out of what God says
your name your very name should remind
you that I will call you out of every
health situation that same can possibly
put you in you are the called out ones
not only as a church are we called out
but as individuals God calls you out so
no matter what the hellish situation is
God says stay faithful to me because
remember you are a called out one I will
call you out I will deliver you I will
set you free
this is why revelation 1:18 is so
important to us beloved because
revelation 1:18 says this I am he that
liveth and was once what's he saying he
went through hell hey I am the one that
went through hell for you now behold I
am Alive for evermore amen and have the
keys of hell and death did you get went
the next time you're struggling with a
situation the next time you're
struggling with a hellish scenario just
remember why Christ has the key to this
situation
look this key you know there are two
reasons you want a key one to get in or
two to get out and this is not Christ
telling us hey I've got the key to let
you into hell that's not what he's
saying nobody wants the key for that
reason beloved we all want the key out
and he's saying listen guys good news I
have the key
no matter what your situation I have the
key no matter what you're going through
I have the key no matter what Satan
brings upon you I have the key listen
God's goal is to get us through hell
don't stop in Hell go through it don't
get caught up in Hell go through it
that's what God's goal is for us I just
want to remind you of three guys
Shadrach Meshach and Abednego you
remember the bad situation they were in
their hellish circumstances they were in
died down or we're going to throw you
into a fiery place down or we're gonna
throw you we're gonna send you to hell
first-class ticket but Shadrach Meshach
and Abednego knew that Jesus had the key
to death and he'll and when they were
thrown in the fire when they were thrown
in the fire
you see they went did they go through
hell they went through hell amen amen
they went through hell the fires could
not stop them nothing Satan did to
destroy them would be accomplished
because Christ was with them Isaiah 43
verse 2 Isaiah 43 verse 2 I want you to
notice it Isaiah 43 verse 2 says this
where's my water Isaiah 43 verse 2 when
thou passes through the waters I will
what I will be with thee and through the
rivers they shall not overflow thee when
thou walkest through the fire just stop
for a second when you walk
not into but through when you walk
through the fire thou shalt not be
burned neither saw the flame Kindle upon
thee Satan will try to lead you into
hell in your marriage he will try to
lead you into hell in your church he
will try to lead you into hell in your
job and listen in the process he will
try to infect you with a hellish spirit
did you catch what I'm saying when Satan
brings a hellish situation into your
life it is for the goal not only to
separate you from God but to infect you
with the spirit of Hell with the
mentality of Hell with the attitude of
Hell thus producing what Jesus call a
child of Hell where are you talking
about the Pharisees and you Traverse and
go all over to make a convert and then
you make them into a child of hell what
is a child of hell a child of hell does
what the kingdom of hell does is a child
of Satan Satan wants to wants to infuse
his principles of his kingdom in your
heart his character he even tried to
infect Christ with hell so look man
they're spitting on you they're mocking
you look at everything they're doing for
you against you but beloved Christ would
not take upon the spirit of hell
seven verse 24 Matthew chapter 7 verse
24 want you to notice these words Jesus
speaking says this therefore whosoever
heareth these sayings of mine and doeth
them I will liken him unto a wise man
which built his house upon a rock and
the rain descended and the floods came
and the winds blew and beat upon that
house and it fell not for it was founded
upon a rock hmm the house doesn't fall
bill of it the house goes through hell
did you catch that the house goes
through hell listen bill I I thought
this was interesting you know it says
three things there would be rain and
then flood and then winds do you
remember where did where else did it
rain that it destroyed a whole bunch of
people remember noah's noah's I remember
that what what happened with Noah's Ark
did it rain and then did it flood and
then the gods send out a mighty east
wind so watch this rain flood and then
wind and it rained when it rained it was
because the people had rejected Noah's
message remember that the rain lifted up
Noah's Ark above the earth man on wood
lifted up above the earth and those who
rejected him were destroyed by the rain
so fast were you going to listen
carefully did God
reject the people because they rejected
his son at the cross did that happen the
god reject a people who rejected his son
of the cross that God gave a prophecy
that said you have X amount of time to
to accept my plan of salvation and if
you don't you will be cut off
yeah so that house their house fell
but God raised up his church in the book
of Revelation chapter 12 the Bible says
the dragon let out of his mouth water as
a flood that's the 1260 years let me ask
you that the church go through hell for
1260 years yeah they went through him
but you know why they stood firm you
know why they went through hell and did
not perish in hell it's because they
were founded upon a rock the house
withstood hell at the end of the 2300
day prophecy z' at the which is still
future in other words 1844 but that
continues on to the close of probation
at the end of time will there be winds
that are let loose that are designed to
destroy the house of God will that be a
hellish time for the people of God but
guess what we need not fair
why because God's church was built on a
rock and despite the trials and the
tribulations and all that will come
against God's house it will stand
we need to rejoice about that beloved as
we look at our world church and we see
things going on in the church and well
man you know our church what's happening
to our church just know that God's house
will stand just know that God's house
will stand when we look at our churches
when we look at things happening in the
church when we look at our families we
look at all these things just remember
this that despite how much it might look
that Satan has the upper hand despite
how much it might look like Satan has
got this thing wrapped up and oh look at
what's happening in this church or that
church or my church or my family my home
just remember that Jesus went through
hell for you for this church so that no
matter what the devil tries to do his
church
is gonna stand now I got one more thing
to share with you beloved and then we're
gonna close but you need to hear this
because the question is how do I go
through hell how many of you would like
to go through hell now
you still like her I don't know faster
yeah yeah yeah yeah listen God is not
gonna back you want to go to hell great
let me know that's not what's gonna
happen don't be superstitious come on
come on come on I want to go through it
not into it because listen beloved every
one of us faces hell every one of us
faces hell so the question is how do I
get through it well Jesus remember when
Jesus was leaving and he said I'm gonna
send you somebody I'm gonna send you the
comforter and the comforter is gonna
guide you comforter is gonna do what
guide you into all truth guide you the
comforter is going to lead you so listen
carefully what is the comfort how does a
comforter lead us it's beautiful
how many of you praise God that he does
not lead us into temptation he leads us
through it but beloved the way to get
through temptation the way the Holy
Spirit designs to get us through hell is
by giving us the fruit of the Spirit so
the way that I make it through hell is I
have to have love I have to have joy I
have to have peace long-suffering
gentleness goodness faith meekness
temperance and if I have these things
those things will secure my passage
through hell
acts 14:22
none of them in a revelation 7:9 15 you
got to see this we got three more three
more texts than we closed revelation 7
verse 9 in revelation 7 verse 9 the
Bible says here after this I beheld and
lo a great multitude which no man could
number of all nations and Kindred's and
peoples and tongues stood before the
throne and before the lamb clothed with
white robes and palms in their hands and
cried with a loud voice saying salvation
to our God which sitteth upon the throne
and unto the lamb and all the Angels
stood round about the throne and about
the elders and the four beasts and fell
before the throne on their faces and
worshipped God saying amen blessing and
glory and wisdom and Thanksgiving and
honour and power and might be unto our
God for ever and ever amen
and one of the elders saying say I
answered saying unto me what are these
which are arrayed in arrayed in white
robes and whence came they where are
these coming from where are these this
great multitude of people in heaven
where are they coming from and his
answer is let me rephrase I rephrase
this his answer is they came out of hell
his answer is they came from Great
Tribulation
in other words but I listen carefully
those who enter heaven must go through
hell no no everyone who enters heaven
will have gotten there because they went
through the next time you hear going
through hell you should rejoice going
through hell no no going through hell
yeah those who enter heaven are those
who went through hell not
in a symbolic sense they went through
tribulation and went through trial but
in a very literal sense yes they died in
the grave hell them but through Christ's
death burial and resurrection and
through obedience to God if you love me
keep my Commandments they the graves
opened up for them and they can say yes
I went through hell because of Jesus
acts 14:22 look at it acts 14 verse 22
the Bible says it very clearly acts 14
verse 22 confirming the souls of the
disciples and exhorting them to continue
in the faith and that we must through
what through much tribulation guys enter
the kingdom of heaven through through
don't be discouraged when you face hell
don't be discouraged when you find
yourself in the midst of a situation
where you're like how am I gonna houses
gonna don't be discouraged because if
you're walking with God he will lead you
through it
everyone that is in heaven would have
gotten there because they went through
hell here's the good news after Saul
said and done but of Revelation 20 verse
13 and 14 revelation 20 verse 13 and
fourth I'm going to invite Terry to come
up he's going to lead us in prayer
revelation 20 verse 13 and 14 the Bible
says and the sea gave up the Dead which
were in it and death and he'll delivered
up the Dead which were which were what
which were what everyone in
why are they in them because they did
not go through them
death caught them hell caught them and
the reason it caught them in the grave
is because it caught them in life they
did not know what it meant to go through
hell instead they stayed in hell they
visited in hell they became citizens of
Hell beloved God says we ought to be
pilgrims of this world just passing
through
this is hell I know it but I'm just
passing through I don't live here I'm
not a citizen of Hell I'm not a captive
of hell
so death and he'll delivered up the Dead
which were in them and they were judged
every man according to their words and
verse 14 says this and death and he'll
were cast into the lake of fire this is
the second death beloved after this
there is no more hell no more hell to go
through God destroys it he leads us
through it and then he destroys it Lord
lead us help me not to be discouraged
when I face these trying situations help
me not to be discouraged when I am
looking ahead and seeing nothing but
darkness nothing but hell God says trust
me I will walk you through this I will
walk you through this Terry